type Question = {
  question: string;
  answers: string[];
  correctAnswer: string;
};


export const H3cellnucleusdata = {
  questions: [
    {
      question: "What is the primary function of the nucleus in a cell?",
      answers: ["Protein synthesis",
       "Lipid metabolism",
       "Command center for cell functions",
       "Energy production",
       "Waste removal"],
      correctAnswer: "Command center for cell functions"
    },
    {
      question: "During interphase, how do macromolecules transfer between the nucleus and cytoplasm?",
      answers: ["Simple diffusion",
       "Osmosis",
       "Pore complexes",
       "Active transport",
       "Endocytosis"],
      correctAnswer: "Pore complexes"
    },
    {
      question: "What structure forms a selectively permeable barrier between the nuclear and cytoplasmic compartments?",
      answers: ["Cell membrane",
       "Nuclear envelope",
       "Cytoskeleton",
       "Golgi apparatus",
       "Endoplasmic reticulum"],
      correctAnswer: "Nuclear envelope"
    },
    {
      question: "What are the two types of chromatin distinguished by their appearance?",
      answers: ["Homochromatin and Heterochromatin",
       "Euchromatin and Heterochromatin",
       "Mesochromatin and Metachromatin",
       "Prochromatin and Pseudochromatin",
       "None of the above"],
      correctAnswer: "Euchromatin and Heterochromatin"
    },
    {
      question: "What does euchromatin represent in a cell?",
      answers: ["Inactive DNA",
       "Mature RNA",
       "Active transcription regions",
       "Condensed DNA",
       "Non-coding RNA"],
      correctAnswer: "Active transcription regions"
    },
    {
      question: "What structure stabilizes the nuclear envelope?",
      answers: ["Nuclear lamina",
       "Chromatin",
       "Nucleolus",
       "Ribosomes",
       "Endoplasmic reticulum"],
      correctAnswer: "Nuclear lamina"
    },
    {
      question: "What proteins are primarily involved in the organization of chromatin?",
      answers: ["Actins",
       "Tubulins",
       "Histones",
       "Keratin",
       "Collagen"],
       correctAnswer: "Histones"
    },
    {
      question: "What is the structural unit of DNA and histones called?",
      answers: ["Chromosome",
       "Nucleosome",
       "Gene",
       "Genome",
       "Nucleolus"],
       correctAnswer: "Nucleosome"
    },
    {
      question: "Which protein provides directionality for macromolecule transport across the nuclear envelope?",
      answers: ["Actin",
       "Tubulin",
       "GTPase",
       "ATPase",
       "DNA polymerase"],
       correctAnswer: "GTPase"
    },
    {
      question: "What is the major component of the nuclear lamina?",
      answers: ["Microtubules",
       "Microfilaments",
       "Lamins",
       "Myosin",
       "Kinesin"],
      correctAnswer: "Lamins"
    },
    {
      question: "Which type of chromatin is visible as lightly stained areas in the light microscope?",
      answers: ["Heterochromatin",
       "Euchromatin",
       "Metachromatin",
       "Prochromatin",
       "None of the above"],
      correctAnswer: "Euchromatin"
    },
    {
      question: "What structure in the nucleus is responsible for ribosome production?",
      answers: ["Nucleolus",
       "Chromatin",
       "Nuclear envelope",
       "Nuclear lamina",
       "Nucleoplasm"],
      correctAnswer: "Nucleolus"
    },
    {
      question: "Which phase of the cell cycle involves the replication of DNA?",
      answers: ["Interphase",
       "Prophase",
       "Metaphase",
       "Anaphase",
       "Telophase"],
      correctAnswer: "Interphase"
    },
    {
      question: "What term is used to describe the total genetic material within a cell?",
      answers: ["Genome",
       "Gene",
       "Nucleotide",
       "Chromosome",
       "Plasmid"],
      correctAnswer: "Genome"
    },
    {
      question: "What is the primary energy source for nuclear transport?",
      answers: ["ATP",
       "GTP",
       "ADP",
       "NADH",
       "FADH2"],
      correctAnswer: "GTP"
    },
    {
      question: "What are the structural units of chromatin that involve DNA wrapped around histone proteins?",
      answers: ["Genes",
       "Exons",
       "Nucleosomes",
       "Introns",
       "Plasmids"],
      correctAnswer: "Nucleosomes"
    },
    {
      question: "Which molecule is used to power the transport of proteins across the nuclear envelope?",
      answers: ["ATP",
       "GTP",
       "CTP",
       "UTP",
       "ADP"],
      correctAnswer: "GTP"
    },
    {
      question: "What forms the structural unit called the nucleosome?",
      answers: ["DNA and ribosomes",
       "DNA and histones",
       "RNA and histones",
       "Proteins and lipids",
       "Lipids and carbohydrates"],
      correctAnswer: "DNA and histones"
    },
    {
      question: "What is the function of nucleoporins in the nuclear pore complex?",
      answers: ["Regulate protein synthesis",
       "Regulate DNA replication",
       "Regulate macromolecule transfer",
       "Regulate RNA transcription",
       "Regulate lipid metabolism"],
      correctAnswer: "Regulate macromolecule transfer"
    },
    {
      question: "What are Barr bodies associated with?",
      answers: ["Male cells",
       "Female cells",
       "Somatic cells",
       "Germ cells",
       "All cells"],
      correctAnswer: "Female cells"
    },
    {
      question: "What is the structural composition of nucleosomes?",
      answers: ["Eight histones and DNA",
       "Four histones and DNA",
       "Two histones and DNA",
       "Six histones and DNA",
       "Ten histones and DNA"],
      correctAnswer: "Eight histones and DNA"
    },
    {
      question: "What term describes the densely packed, inactive form of chromatin?",
      answers: ["Euchromatin",
       "Metachromatin",
       "Heterochromatin",
       "Prochromatin",
       "Pseudochromatin"],
      correctAnswer: "Heterochromatin"
    },
    {
      question: "What cell structure is continuous with the outer nuclear membrane?",
      answers: ["Golgi apparatus",
       "Mitochondria",
       "Rough endoplasmic reticulum",
       "Smooth endoplasmic reticulum",
       "Lysosomes"],
      correctAnswer: "Rough endoplasmic reticulum"
    },
    {
      question: "Which proteins are involved in the formation of the nuclear lamina?",
      answers: ["Tubulins",
       "Actins",
       "Lamins",
       "Keratins",
       "Myosins"],
      correctAnswer: "Lamins"
    },
    {
      question: "What are chromosomes composed of?",
      answers: ["DNA and RNA",
       "DNA and proteins",
       "RNA and proteins",
       "Proteins and lipids",
       "Lipids and carbohydrates"],
      correctAnswer: "DNA and proteins"
    },
    {
      question: "What is the function of the nuclear lamina?",
      answers: ["Regulate DNA replication",
       "Regulate RNA transcription",
       "Stabilize the nuclear envelope",
       "Facilitate protein synthesis",
       "Control lipid metabolism"],
      correctAnswer: "Stabilize the nuclear envelope"
    },
    {
      question: "What is the primary function of euchromatin?",
      answers: ["DNA packaging",
       "Protein degradation",
       "Active transcription",
       "Cellular respiration",
       "Lipid metabolism"],
      correctAnswer: "Active transcription"
    },
    {
      question: "What type of chromatin appears as coarse, electron-dense material in the electron microscope?",
      answers: ["Euchromatin",
       "Metachromatin",
       "Heterochromatin",
       "Prochromatin",
       "Pseudochromatin"],
      correctAnswer: "Heterochromatin"
    },
    {
      question: "Which component of the nuclear pore complex displays eightfold symmetry around the lumen?",
      answers: ["Lamins",
       "Nucleoporins",
       "Histones",
       "Keratins",
       "Myosins"],
      correctAnswer: "Nucleoporins"
    },
    {
      question: "What is the role of the nucleolus in the cell?",
      answers: ["Lipid synthesis",
       "Ribosome production",
       "Protein degradation",
       "RNA splicing",
       "DNA replication"],
      correctAnswer: "Ribosome production"
    }
  ] as Question[]
};
  